<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Conejo Valley Unitarian Universalist Fellowship Audio Sermons</title>
  <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons.html</link>
  <description>CVUUF Selected Audio Sermons</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2015 02:16:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>ListGarden Program 1.3.1</generator>
  <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
  <item>
   <title>Love Came Down at Christmas</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141221.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
December 21, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
The story of Christ's nativity makes sense on a mythological level. Joining the story of one lowly-born in a manger among the animals with the stories of other gods and heroes celebrated at the time of the Winter Solstice makes mythological sense. In the nineteenth century poet Christina Rossetti wrote, &quot;Love came down at Christmas, love all lovely, love divine,&quot; capturing the essence of our deep yearning for the transcendent. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141221.mp3" length="5236767" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 23:05:25 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141221.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Mystery and Wonder</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141214.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
December 14, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
The gift of this time of year is to be reminded to gaze at our lives through the eyes of a child. We are reminded of mystery and wonder and the potential for joy in the smallest moments. Remaining open, we allow ourselves to be immersed in the darkness of the shortest days of the year and with faith we wait for the light to reappear. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141214.mp3" length="6708767" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 23:03:22 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141214.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>The Work of Loving the World</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141207.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
December 7, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
The sermon description goes here.&quot;My work is loving the world,&quot; writes the poet Mary Oliver. It is easy to love the world of the poet: &quot;the phoebe, the delphinium, the sheep in the pasture, and the pasture.&quot; It is difficult to love the world when it is torn apart by injustice, especially when we are unable to come to consensus as to what justice looks like. Our work is to love the world, no matter what. 
</description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141207.mp3" length="6755657" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 23:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141207.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>The Gospel According to Kurt</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141130.mp3</link>
   <description>by Merlin Snider&lt;br&gt;
November 30, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Gospel is one of those words that do double duty. It means a life story, like the gospels in the Bible. It also means some incredibly important kernel of truth. The &quot;gospel truth.&quot; Fellowship member Merlin Snider tells the tale of how in graduate school he found the life and work of Kurt Vonnegut, self-described as &quot;simultaneously a humorist and a serious novelist.&quot; Like Billy Pilgrim, his famous character from Slaughterhouse Five, Vonnegut came unstuck in time because of the horrible things he had witnessed, and in Vonnegut's heroic, anti-heroic way, managed to describe our human condition with dark humor, compassion, and ultimately hope. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141130.mp3" length="6983706" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 02:06:23 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141130.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Gratitude and Reverence</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141123.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
November 23, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Gratitude and reverence are important to humanist teachings. Reverence is not just about a feeling associated with a deity. Meister Eckhart supposedly said, “If the only prayer you say in your life is thank you that would suffice.” Cicero’s quote works better for those who don’t pray: “Gratitude is not only the greatest of virtues, but the parent of all others.” Reason does not preclude gratitude and reverence, particularly during this time of year.
</description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141123.mp3" length="5333943" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 02:04:36 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141123.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>A Letter to My Ex-husband the Atheist</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141116.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
November 16, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
My ex-husband the atheist has become a character in several of my sermons, serving as a foil to my pious religiosity. First of all, I am not really piously religious and secondly my ex-husband the atheist is more than a character in my sermons. But he has railed against religion enough on his Facebook feed that I feel that I must finally respond with this letter. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141116.mp3" length="6031958" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 02:02:42 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141116.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>A Humanist Language of Reverence</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141109.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
November 9, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
In 2003 when William Sinkford, then the president of our denomination, preached a sermon calling for UUs to reclaim a vocabulary of reverence including the word God, it made the national news. Religious language doesn’t have to mean we use the word God, but it does mean that we have to consciously select how we speak to each other as members of a religious community. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141109.mp3" length="5719920" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 02:01:05 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141109.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>We Are All Humanists</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141102.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
November 2, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
A neighbor asked William R. Murry what he meant when he said he was a humanist. He replied that, “humanism refers to the affirmation of the worth and dignity of every person, a commitment to human betterment, and the necessity for human beings to take responsibility for themselves and the world.” With that definition we are all humanists, but there are also different kinds of humanists who attend UU congregations – religious humanists. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141102.mp3" length="6050880" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 01:58:42 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141102.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Everyday Heroes</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141019.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
October 19, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Unitarian Universalists are proud to recite the standard litanies of famous UUs as a way of explaining who we are. There are also everyday heroes in our history who shaped our religion and confronted powers and structures of evil. There are also everyday heroes in our faith tradition today who continue to affirm and promote justice, compassion and the transforming power of love as a way of living our values in the world. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141019.mp3" length="5806890" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 01:50:18 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141019.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Words and Deeds of Prophetic Women and Men</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141012.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
October 12, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Our religion has a long history filled with the words and deeds of prophetic women and men. We are known for our acts of social justice because of the words and deeds of women and men like Susan B. Anthony, Clara Barton, Horace Greeley, John Marshall, Joseph Priestly, and others who are remembered for speaking truth to power. Inspired by the past, we are challenged to transform the world with justice and compassion. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141012.mp3" length="6086792" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 01:42:19 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141012.mp3</guid>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
