<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Conejo Valley Unitarian Universalist Fellowship Audio Sermons</title>
  <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons.html</link>
  <description>CVUUF Selected Audio Sermons</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 22:21:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>ListGarden Program 1.3.1</generator>
  <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
  <item>
   <title>A Ministry of Presence</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150125.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
January 25, 2015&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Many of us are first drawn to a church community during a time of transition in our lives. A loved one dies, we're going through a divorce, we want our children to have a liberal religious education. At first, we attend the &quot;church of the me&quot; only getting our own needs met. Soon we discover that being in beloved community means our presence is needed to minister to others. No longer satisfied with just getting our needs met each Sunday, we come to church to serve. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150125.mp3" length="5565184" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 22:18:41 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150125.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Why Selma Matters</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150118.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
January 18, 2015&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Mark Morrison-Reed writes, &quot;For Unitarian Universalism, whose most progressive elements had long been champions of freedom in its broadest sense, Selma was a test.&quot; Fifty years ago, Unitarian Universalists were challenged to answer Dr. King's call and show up in Selma. Many did; two died. What was Selma's impact on our religious movement? What do the events of fifty years ago mean to us today when the streets of our country are filled with people holding signs proclaiming &quot;black lives matter?&quot; </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150118.mp3" length="5578360" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 22:17:34 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150118.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Beloved Community</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150111.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
January 11, 2015&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
As Unitarian Universalists we strive to create beloved community - a community where love is present. It sounds simple enough, but most of us hear the struggle behind the label, the complexity lurking just below the surface. Still we strive; we dream dreams and we have visions.</description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150111.mp3" length="5790264" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 22:16:33 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon150111.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Love Came Down at Christmas</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141221.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
December 21, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
The story of Christ's nativity makes sense on a mythological level. Joining the story of one lowly-born in a manger among the animals with the stories of other gods and heroes celebrated at the time of the Winter Solstice makes mythological sense. In the nineteenth century poet Christina Rossetti wrote, &quot;Love came down at Christmas, love all lovely, love divine,&quot; capturing the essence of our deep yearning for the transcendent. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141221.mp3" length="5236767" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 23:05:25 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141221.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Mystery and Wonder</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141214.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
December 14, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
The gift of this time of year is to be reminded to gaze at our lives through the eyes of a child. We are reminded of mystery and wonder and the potential for joy in the smallest moments. Remaining open, we allow ourselves to be immersed in the darkness of the shortest days of the year and with faith we wait for the light to reappear. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141214.mp3" length="6708767" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 23:03:22 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141214.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>The Work of Loving the World</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141207.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
December 7, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
The sermon description goes here.&quot;My work is loving the world,&quot; writes the poet Mary Oliver. It is easy to love the world of the poet: &quot;the phoebe, the delphinium, the sheep in the pasture, and the pasture.&quot; It is difficult to love the world when it is torn apart by injustice, especially when we are unable to come to consensus as to what justice looks like. Our work is to love the world, no matter what. 
</description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141207.mp3" length="6755657" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 23:01:59 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141207.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>The Gospel According to Kurt</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141130.mp3</link>
   <description>by Merlin Snider&lt;br&gt;
November 30, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Gospel is one of those words that do double duty. It means a life story, like the gospels in the Bible. It also means some incredibly important kernel of truth. The &quot;gospel truth.&quot; Fellowship member Merlin Snider tells the tale of how in graduate school he found the life and work of Kurt Vonnegut, self-described as &quot;simultaneously a humorist and a serious novelist.&quot; Like Billy Pilgrim, his famous character from Slaughterhouse Five, Vonnegut came unstuck in time because of the horrible things he had witnessed, and in Vonnegut's heroic, anti-heroic way, managed to describe our human condition with dark humor, compassion, and ultimately hope. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141130.mp3" length="6983706" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 02:06:23 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141130.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Gratitude and Reverence</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141123.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
November 23, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Gratitude and reverence are important to humanist teachings. Reverence is not just about a feeling associated with a deity. Meister Eckhart supposedly said, “If the only prayer you say in your life is thank you that would suffice.” Cicero’s quote works better for those who don’t pray: “Gratitude is not only the greatest of virtues, but the parent of all others.” Reason does not preclude gratitude and reverence, particularly during this time of year.
</description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141123.mp3" length="5333943" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 02:04:36 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141123.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>A Letter to My Ex-husband the Atheist</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141116.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
November 16, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
My ex-husband the atheist has become a character in several of my sermons, serving as a foil to my pious religiosity. First of all, I am not really piously religious and secondly my ex-husband the atheist is more than a character in my sermons. But he has railed against religion enough on his Facebook feed that I feel that I must finally respond with this letter. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141116.mp3" length="6031958" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 02:02:42 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141116.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>A Humanist Language of Reverence</title>
   <link>http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141109.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
November 9, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
In 2003 when William Sinkford, then the president of our denomination, preached a sermon calling for UUs to reclaim a vocabulary of reverence including the word God, it made the national news. Religious language doesn’t have to mean we use the word God, but it does mean that we have to consciously select how we speak to each other as members of a religious community. </description>
   <enclosure url="http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141109.mp3" length="5719920" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 02:01:05 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">http://cvuuf.org/media/sermons/sermon141109.mp3</guid>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
