<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Conejo Valley Unitarian Universalist Fellowship Audio Sermons</title>
  <link>/media/sermons.html</link>
  <description>CVUUF Selected Audio Sermons</description>
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 09:05:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>ListGarden Program 1.3.1</generator>
  <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
  <item>
   <title>Living in Harmony with Nature</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140921.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
September 21, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Psychologist Mary Pipher writes, "The trauma of our personal lives and the rapidity of the deterioration of our planet are deeply connected." Yet, if we focus on convincing people of the dire nature of our situation without offering tangible solutions, the trauma wound only festers and does not heal. Our sixth principle offers hope during a time when hope is what is needed most. </description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140921.mp3" length="17210052" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 09:00:20 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140921.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Compassion is Possible</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140831.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
August 31, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Karen Armstrong designed the “twelve steps to a compassionate life” as a discipline to give us the tools to break our addiction to our egotism. Although we are never finished on this journey towards living compassionately, today we’ll celebrate the end of our focused time together exploring compassion. We will participate in an ending ritual and receive a token made by the loving hands of the children from our religious education classes. </description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140831.mp3" length="6072552" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 01:33:20 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140831.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Meeting the World's Deep Need</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140727.mp3</link>
   <description>by Carol Flanagan&lt;br&gt;
July 27, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
As we conclude our month of exploring the eleventh step to a compassionate life we are challenged by author Karen Armstrong to look deeply at our world and each find our mission, a need only we can fill. Armstrong's personal journey to find her mission, as shared in her autobiographical works, can inspire us as we struggle to recognize where we can be of service when, in the words of the poet W.B. Yeats, &quot;Too many things are occurring for even a big heart to hold.&quot;
</description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140727.mp3" length="4890442" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 04:43:44 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140727.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Transforming the World through Justice and Compassion</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140713.mp3</link>
   <description>by Pamela Lopez&lt;br&gt;
July 13, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Outreach Director Pamela Lopez will explore the duality of that when we do acts of service we are not only transforming the world, but we are transforming ourselves. Join Pamela and other congregation members who engage in acts of service as they reflect on how those giving acts have transformed the world as well as their own lives.
</description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140713.mp3" length="" type="" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 05:30:12 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140713.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Fathers and Sons</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140615.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
June 15, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
The tenth step to a compassionate life is knowledge and again we begin with ourselves. We begin with our own relationships. It is easy to point the finger of blame towards a society that can’t enact better laws or better mental health services to prevent our sons from erupting in violence. In the wake of the tragedy at Isla Vista we reflect on what it means to be a man in a changing world. On Father’s Day we celebrate the crucial relationship of fathers and sons.
</description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140615.mp3" length="3246447" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 17:33:40 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140615.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Muhammad's Night Journey</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140525.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
May 25, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Muhammad’s Night Journey reverses the typical pattern from Arabic poetry that depicts the poet embarking on a night journey and returning joyfully to his tribe. The Prophet Muhammad’s journey to Jerusalem and his Ascension to Heaven describe an archetypal truth rather than a factual truth. It is a journey beyond ego to reunification with the whole human family. It is a journey toward concern for everybody.</description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140525.mp3" length="4812904" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 17:51:49 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140525.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Malice toward None, Charity for All</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140518.mp3</link>
   <description>by Merlin Snider&lt;br&gt;
May 18, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
We think we know the story of Abraham Lincoln, how he came from humble frontier beginnings, became a self-taught lawyer and our 16th President, signed the Emancipation Proclamation, authored the Gettysburg Address, preserved the Union, only to die tragically at the hands of an assassin. We know he suffered great personal losses in his family, but we know less about how he suffered from a life-long depression, how he managed it, and used it empathetically to show concern for everybody, friends and enemies alike, &quot;with malice toward none and charity for all.&quot;
</description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140518.mp3" length="6547399" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 18:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140518.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>How Should We Listen to One Another?</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140413.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
April 13, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
We usually think of listening as something passive. We want to act, to listen and to offer advice or argue our position. Listening is a different kind of “doing” where we offer our presence as a gift freely given. True listening means that we listen with our entire beings to not just the words being spoken, but also to the way the words are said, to what is underneath the words. Listening well we learn to trust that our presence is enough; our focused attention does make a difference. </description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140413.mp3" length="5019811" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 18:47:08 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140413.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>How Should We Speak to One Another?</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140406.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
April 6, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
Our faith is guided by a set of ethical principles sustained by wisdom found in a variety of sources that religious people throughout the ages have turned to for practical steps in order to live with integrity. As members of this Fellowship we covenant to speak honestly and directly to someone with whom we disagree or have a concern. We assume good intentions and use compassionate language in our exchanges with each other. Sometimes we fall short, knowing that we can be called back into covenant to continue to learn how we should and can speak to one another.
</description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140406.mp3" length="6787409" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 19:09:50 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140406.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>The Unexamined Life is Not Worth Living</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140309.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis&lt;br&gt;
March 9, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
The phrase “the unexamined life is not worth living” has been attributed to Socrates. He also claimed that he knew nothing and was wiser than most because at least he admitted that he knew that he knew nothing. History is full of great thinkers who promote doubt as a means to discover truth. Admitting that we know nothing is to embrace doubt. It is also the way to live an examined life.
</description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140309.mp3" length="5406728" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 19:52:11 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140309.mp3</guid>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>The Loving Brain</title>
   <link>/media/sermons/sermon140209.mp3</link>
   <description>by Rev. Lora Brandis
&lt;br&gt;Presented February 9, 2014
&lt;p&gt;
In the book Buddha's Brain, clinical psychologist Rick Hanson and neurologist Richard Mendius examine the lives of the great teachers like Buddha, Jesus and Muhammad concluding that these great spiritual leaders changed their brains in ways that changed the world. We can learn from these great teachers and the latest breakthroughs in neuroscience to find out how we too can use our minds to shape our brains for greater happiness, love, and wisdom. </description>
   <enclosure url="/media/sermons/sermon140209.mp3" length="6322585" type="audio/mpeg" />
   <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 04:48:48 GMT</pubDate>
   <guid isPermaLink="true">/media/sermons/sermon140209.mp3</guid>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
